(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
あ、あ、あー。
Ah, ah, ah...
えー、本日は、さくらみこ
Umm, today, to Sakura Miko's
4th Birthday Party Virtual Live 2022に
4th Birthday Party Virtual Live 2022,
ご来場いただき、誠にありがとうございます！
thank you very much for attending!
皆さん、にゃっはろー！影ナレのさくらみこです。
Nyahallo, everyone! It's your backstage announcer, Sakura Miko.
本日、18.4歳になりました！
Today, I've turned 18.4 years old!
えへへっ。ちょっとあれだな、影ナレっぽく読もう。
Ehehe. Wait, let me read more like an actual announcer.
えー、あー、開演に先立ちまして、
Ahem. Prior to the start of the performance,
ご来場のお客様にお願い申し上げます。
we have a few requests for our guests.
客席内での飲食は、
Regarding eating and drinking in the audience area,
ご遠慮なく平らげていただいても構いません！
please feel free to finish it all without hesitation!
自由に盛り上がってもらってOKです！
It's totally OK to get hyped up however you like!
むしろ、どわさっとハッシュタグ
In fact, go wild using the hashtag
#さくらみこ生誕祭 で呟きながら盛り上がりまくってください！
#SakuraMikoSeitansai and keep that energy going!
また、スクショで18.4歳になった
Also, please take lots of screenshots of me,
このエリートさくらみこちゃんを
this elite Sakura Miko-chan who is now 18.4,
たくさん撮って投稿してくださいね！
and post them online!
それでは、間もなく開演でございます。
And now, the show is about to begin.
みんな！みこのバースデーパーティー楽しんでいってね！
Everyone! Have a blast at Miko's birthday party!
行くよ！
Let's go!
どーまいべすと！ 作詞/作曲：キノシタ
Do My Best! Lyrics/Composition: kinoshita
じゃんじゃーん！
Ta-da!
はちゃめちゃカラフルデイズ 攻略法を探している
Searching for a walkthrough for these messy, colorful days
リセットボタンなんてあるわけないし
It's not like there's a reset button
縛りプレイもいい所じゃない？！
Isn't this "restricted play" kind of nice?!
そんなのは分かりきってる
I know that full well
それなら思い出して
If that's the case, remember
夢を奏でるあの星のことを
Those stars that play out our dreams
最初はダメダメでもいいからさ
It's okay if it's no good at first
ほらリズムに合わせて Try & Try!
Look, match the rhythm and Try & Try!
予測不可能なんだ 本当のところ
To be honest, it's unpredictable
次のページのことだよ？
Like what's on the next page, you know?
I know
怖いことなんてないよ その続きに
There's nothing to fear in what comes next
いっせーので飛び込んじゃおう
Let's dive in on the count of three
準備はいーい？
Are you ready?
だから Do my best! Do my best! テンションは弾けてくらり
So Do my best! Do my best! Tension is bursting and spinning
こっち向いて Attention Please? Attention Please? ドキドキのボリュームMAX
Look this way, Attention Please? Attention Please? Heart-pounding volume at MAX
泣いちゃって笑っちゃって エモーションもアタフタしてる
Crying and laughing, emotions are all in a fluster
この今をめいっぱいさ楽しんでいこうよ
Let's enjoy this moment to the fullest
まだまだまだなの止まれない そんな世界が大好きだよ
It's still not enough, I can't stop, I love a world like this
声に出して Do my best!
Shout it out, Do my best!
ちんぷんかんぷんカラフルデイズ
Gibberish colorful days
冒険の書はどこにもない
There's no adventure log anywhere
セーブポイントやり直しの毎日じゃ
If it's just a daily routine of save points and retries
ワクワクの音色も奏でられない
You can't play the melody of excitement
そんなのつまんないでしょ？
That's boring, isn't it?
それなら耳を澄まして
Then listen closely
大好きな音が聞こえてくるよ
You'll hear your favorite sounds
明日は明日の風が吹くからさ
Because tomorrow the wind will blow for tomorrow
ほらリズムに合わせて 1 2 Try & Try!
Look, match the rhythm, 1 2 Try & Try!
やっぱ気になっちゃうな 本当のところ
I guess I am curious, to be honest
次のページのことだよ？
Like what's on the next page, you know?
I want to know
あふれるリズム繋いで
Connect the overflowing rhythms
君だけの気持ちを今すぐ描いちゃおう
Let's draw out your feelings right now
うーーーっ、すっげー！
Oooooh, amazing!
だから Do my best! Do my best! クエスチョンがぐるぐる回る
So Do my best! Do my best! Questions are spinning round and round
白昼夢中 Attention Please? Attention Please? キラキラのボリューム全開
Daydreaming, Attention Please? Attention Please? Sparkling volume full throttle
単純で明快な エモーションにアタフタして
Getting flustered over simple and clear emotions
これからもめいっぱいさ 仲良くよろしくね
Let's keep being good friends from now on too
まだまだまだあとどれくらい？ そんな明日を目指して行こう
Still a long way, how much longer? Let's aim for that tomorrow
行こうもう一歩！ Do my best!
Let's go one more step! Do my best!
お星様にお願い事 早くそれになれますように
A wish upon a star, I hope I can become that soon
覚めないように魔法をかけて
Cast a spell so I don't wake up
ワクワクが爆発しちゃいそう！
This excitement is about to explode!
どっかーん！
Boom!
今日はみこの誕生日パーティー！
Today is Miko's Birthday Party!
ゲストもいっぱい出るよ！
Lots of guests will be here too!
みんな、楽しんでってね！
Everyone, please enjoy!
今気づいちゃったんだ 本当のところは
I just realized now, the truth is
次のページのことだよ？
Like what's on the next page, you know?
I can't wait
楽しみすぎるからさ その続きに
Because I'm looking forward to what comes next too much
いっせーので飛び込んじゃおう
Let's dive in on the count of three
準備はいーい？
Are you ready?
だから Do my best! Do my best! テンションは弾けてくらり
So Do my best! Do my best! Tension is bursting and spinning
こっち向いて Attention Please? Attention Please? ドキドキのボリュームMAX
Look this way, Attention Please? Attention Please? Heart-pounding volume at MAX
泣いちゃって笑っちゃって エモーションもアタフタしてる
Crying and laughing, emotions are all in a fluster
この今をめいっぱいさ 楽しんでいこうよ
Let's enjoy this moment to the fullest
まだまだまだなの止まれない そんな世界に大好き宣言
It's still not enough, I can't stop, declaring my love for a world like this
声に出して Do my best!
Shout it out, Do my best!
合言葉はー？
What's the password?
どーまいべすと！
Do my best!
行くぞー！
Here we go!
はい！頑張ろうなぎ！
Yes! Let's do our best!
うー、せんきゅー！
Ooh, thank you!
どぞ、まふまふ！
Thanks much-much!
さん、はい！
Three, go!
Booo! 作詞/作曲：TOKOTOKO
Booo! Lyrics/Composition: TOKOTOKO
また始まった
It started again
また始まった 忘れん坊
It's starting again, you forgetful one
手帳の隅っこだって
Even in the corner of your notebook
カレンダーにだって
And even on your calendar
マルしておいたのに
I'd circled it for you
どうして怒ってるか おわかりですか?
Do you understand why I'm angry?
謝っても許さないんだからね もう知らない!
Even if you apologize, I won't forgive you! I don't care anymore!
どこにでもあるような どこにもないような
Something you can find anywhere, but can't find anywhere
シアワセ探しましょう また始まったわがまま
Let's look for happiness. My selfishness has started again
楽しみにしてたプリンだって
Even the pudding I was looking forward to
君に食べられる為に生まれたわけじゃなかったのに
Wasn't born just to be eaten by you
どー
No-
それちょっとだけちょうだい
Give me just a little bit of that
ねえひと口だけちょうだいなんて
Hey, saying "give me just one bite"
あまりにも都合が良すぎじゃないの?
Isn't that just a bit too convenient?
飽きちゃったらいらない
If you get bored, you don't want it
残しちゃったらごめんなさいって
If you leave some, saying "I'm sorry"
...君のせいかしら?
...Is it because of you?
一体全体 私のことも
Overall, about me
どれくらい愛してるって
How much do you love me?
言葉じゃなくて形で欲しいのです
I want it in the form of actions, not words
今日が何の日か お忘れですか?
Have you forgotten what day it is today?
でも誕生日なんて言うのもちょっと癪ね もう知らない!
But it's a bit annoying to even say it's my birthday! I don't care anymore!
結婚するとかしないとか
To marry or not to marry
子供は何人欲しいとか
How many children you want
シアワセ家族計画掲げる前に
Before you lay out your happy family plan
タバコやお酒は控えるとか
Refraining from smoking and drinking
明日から真面目にやるとか
Or doing things seriously from tomorrow
だらだら続いているじゃじゃじゃじゃじゃ
You're just dragging it out, ja-ja-ja-ja-ja!
それちょっとだけちょうだい
Give me just a little bit of that
ねえひと口だけちょうだいなんて
Hey, saying "give me just one bite"
あまりにも都合が良すぎじゃないの?
Isn't that just a bit too convenient?
飽きちゃったらいらない
If you get bored, you don't want it
残しちゃったらごめんなさいって
If you leave some, saying "I'm sorry"
...君のせいかしら?
...Is it because of you?
ひと口だけちょうだい
Give me just one bite
もうひと口だけちょうだいなんて
Hey, saying "give me just one more bite"
甘え上手って罪なんじゃないの?
Isn't being good at being spoiled a sin?
ちょっとだけちょうだい
Give me just a little bit
ねえ出来たら全部ちょうだいなんて
Hey, saying "if you can, give me everything"
君のせいかしら?
Is it because of you?
私のせいかしら?
Is it because of me?
やっぱ君のせいかしら?
Is it because of you after all?
おしまい
The end
はーい！というこで、みんなー
Hi! And so, everyone—
にゃっはろー！にゃっはろーにゃっはろー！
Nyahallo! Nyahallo-nyahallo!
はい、ということで本日の主役、さくらみこでーす！
Yes, so, today's protagonist is Sakura Miko!
イエーイ！どうみんなー？
Yay! How is everyone?
どうだった？どうだった？可愛かった？
How was it? How was it? Was it cute?
ありがとうみんなー！
Thank you everyone!
はい！ということで皆さん、こちら、あ、こっち。
Yes! And so everyone, over here, ah, this way.
こちらのね、さくらみこ生誕祭でたくさん呟いてくれてますか？
Are you all tweeting a lot with this hashtag, Sakura Miko Birthday Festival?
お、パチパチありがとう、ありがとにゃっはろー。海外ニキも、センキュー、ありがとう。
Oh, thank you for the applause, thank you for the Nyahallo. Overseas bros too, thank you, thank you.
おー可愛かった、ありがとう！
Oh, it was cute, thank you!
ちゅまちゅまちゅま。見て、このねステージもね、めちゃくちゃね、あの、みこ仕様にしていただきまして、本当にありがとうございます。
Kiss kiss kiss. Look, this stage too, it's been made totally Miko-style, thank you so much.
ということで！
And so!
この後は、ゲストパート！ゲストパートがありますので、
After this, the guest part! There will be a guest part, so...
皆さん、最後まで絶対見に、お、見てってね！
Everyone, please make sure to watch until the very end!
それじゃあゲストパート、レッツゴー！
Well then, guest part, let's go!
神のまにまに
Kami no Manimani
よー、ぽんぽん！
Yo, pon-pon!
思い通りにいかないことだらけ
Things just don't go as planned
どうしようもなく自己嫌悪
I'm helplessly in self-loathing
八百万の痛みや悲しみから
From the countless pains and sorrows
逃げ込める場所を探してる
I'm looking for a place to hide
指岩戸の隙間にひきこもって
Shutting myself in the gap of the rock door
太陽も無視して寝よう
Ignoring even the sun, let's sleep
生まれてきたことの意味なんて知らない、わかんないよ
I don't know the meaning of being born, I don't understand
でもそんな風に思えるってことは
But being able to think like that
君がもっともっと素敵になれる力...
Is proof that you have the power to become even more wonderful...
...あるって　教えてるんだよ
...that it exists," they're teaching us.
そうさ　神のまにまに　仰せのまにまに
That's right, at god's mercy, as they command.
誰だって地球を愛してる
Everyone loves the Earth.
飲めや歌えやどんちゃん騒ぎ
Drink, sing, and have a rowdy party;
たまにゃそんなんもいいね
sometimes that's okay too.
そうさ北も南も右も左も
That's right, north, south, right, and left.
なんだかんだ地球を愛してる
One way or another, we love the Earth.
泥んこだけど歩いて行ける
Even if we're covered in mud, we can keep walking.
まだまだ先は長いさ
There's still a long way to go.
鏡出した　独りでいたんだけ
I took out a mirror; I was just alone.
きっと誰もがそう願っているけど
Surely everyone wishes for that, but...
八百万の心に耳澄ませ
Listen closely to the hearts of the millions of gods.
苦しめられない　毎日さ
In these days where we can't be tormented...
僕が生まれてきたこと
The fact that I was born...
奇跡と言えば聞こえはいいけど
...sounds nice if you call it a miracle, but...
それはきっと偶然に過ぎなくて
...it's surely nothing more than a coincidence.
やっぱり意味なんてないか
I guess there's no meaning after all.
でも例えば君に意地悪もする
But, for example, even if people are mean to you...
奴が居るならそれは
...if there's someone like that, then...
君がとっても素敵な人だって
...it's because you're such a wonderful person...
教えてるんだよ
...that they're teaching us.
そうさ　神のまにまに　仰せのまにまに
That's right, at god's mercy, as they command.
誰だって地球を愛してる
Everyone loves the Earth.
僕が笑って君も笑えば
If I laugh and you laugh too...
許せないことなんてないよ
...there's nothing that can't be forgiven.
そうさ男も女も恋い焦がれるべき
That's right, men and women should all fall deeply in love.
そんな風に地球は回ってる
That's the way the Earth keeps spinning.
泥んこだけど歩いて行こう
Even if we're covered in mud, let's keep walking.
まだまだ先は長いさ
There's still a long way to go.
本当に大事なものなんて
Things that are truly important...
案外くだらないことの中にあるよ
can be found in unexpectedly trivial things.
ときにはみんなで馬鹿騒ぎ
Sometimes, let's all have a wild party together.
裸踊りで大笑い
Dancing naked and laughing out loud.
そうさ　神のまにまに　仰せのまにまに
That's right, at god's mercy, as they command.
もっともっと自分を愛せるよ
You can love yourself more and more.
鏡を見てごらんよ　もう分かるでしょ
Take a look in the mirror; you'll understand now.
みんなを照らす光さ
You're the light that shines on everyone.
そうさ　神のまにまに　みんなありがとう
That's right, at god's mercy, thank you everyone.
やっぱり地球を愛してる
We love the Earth after all.
花を咲かそう　大きな花を
Let's make flowers bloom, big flowers...
天まで届くくらいの
...that reach all the way to the heavens.
La la la...
寝・逃・げでリセット！
Reset by Sleeping and Running Away!
心配だってないないないないないないないない
No worries, none at all, none, none, none, none, none, none...
どうもまたまたやらかして
It seems I've messed up again...
言い訳してる溜息
...making excuses with a sigh.
何だか少し眠くなり
I'm starting to feel a bit sleepy.
瞼落ちたらお布団が
When my eyelids drop, my futon...
幸せくれるの
...gives me happiness.
フカフカいつもありがとう
Thank you for always being so fluffy.
すぐ生まれて嬉しいな
I'm glad to be born right away.
夢へとユックリユックリ
Slowly, slowly into the dream...
進みましょう　重力が
...let's go. Gravity...
なくなる　ああいい気分だ
...disappears. Ah, it feels so good.
心配だってグッナイ
Even worries, goodnight to them.
寝逃げすることも悪くないよ
Running away by sleeping isn't so bad.
目覚めたら忘れちゃうみんな
When you wake up, everyone will have forgotten.
心配だってドーマイ
Even worries, don't mind them.
朝の眩しさに消えてしまえばいいな
I wish they'd just vanish into the morning brightness.
新しい一日で
With a new day...
リセット！
...Reset!
起きてポヤポヤ手探りで
Waking up all fuzzy, fumbling around...
答えを探す　ビックリした
...looking for answers. I was surprised.
なんで誰か起こしてよ
Why? Someone wake me up!
間に合わないよ　お布団が
I'm not going to make it! My futon...
深呼吸をひとつしたね
You took a deep breath.
焦ってポリ袋さっそく着替えたら
If you rush to change into a plastic bag right away...
閉まらないスカートね
The skirt won't close.
ファスナーを焦れば焦るほど
The more you hurry with the zipper...
最悪ね　布が挟まった
It's the worst, the fabric got caught.
デート待ってるの　ボブカット
Waiting for a date, bob cut.
だんだんたまに余裕持たなくちゃ
Gradually, I need to have some leeway sometimes.
こけてばかりでも　落としちゃったりね
Even if I keep falling or dropping things.
少しだけ　へこむ
I feel a little bit down.
さんざんだ　どんまい靴を履きながら
It's terrible, never mind, while putting on my shoes.
外へ飛び出すきらり
Rushing outside, sparkling.
いいてんき　素敵だね
Good weather, isn't it wonderful?
がんばっちゃおう
Let's do our best.
今更なんて言わないで
Don't say it's too late now.
早朝なんていらないで
I don't need early mornings.
青春なんて知らないで
I don't know about youth.
アセアセギリギリ何年生
Hurrying, at the limit, what grade are you?
紹介なんて聞かないで
Don't ask for an introduction.
想像なんて止めないで
Don't stop the imagination.
エブリデイ　エブリワン
Everyday, everyone.
イェイイェイイェーイ
Yay yay yay.
失敗だってどんまい
Even if I fail, don't mind.
寝逃げするのも悪くないよね
Resetting by sleeping isn't bad either, right?
きっと目が覚めて
Surely when I wake up.
忘れちゃうみんな
Everyone will have forgotten.
失敗だってどんまい
Even if I fail, don't mind.
朝の眩しさに消えてしまえばいいな
I wish it would disappear in the morning brightness.
新しい一日に
For a new day.
リセット
Reset.
ホカホカじかん　ありがと
Thank you for the warm time.
ソトピソカピソカ起きなくちゃ
Need to wake up.
ホカホカで
Feeling warm.
およよってまったり行きたいな
I want to go leisurely.
妄想で慌てて猛ダッシュ
Hurrying with a dash in my imagination.
ホカホカじかん　ありがと
Thank you for the warm time.
ソトピソカピソカ起きなくちゃ
Need to wake up.
ホカホカで
Feeling warm.
およよってまったり行きたいな
I want to go leisurely.
妄想で慌てて猛ダッシュ
Hurrying with a dash in my imagination.
うわった　それなんのことかしら
Oh, I wonder what that's about.
しらんぷり　今日も重ねるの
Feigning ignorance, I repeat it again today.
ちがった　他のでも誰でもなく
No, it's not anyone else.
キミの前で　あーゆーのあいそ
In front of you, that kind of courtesy.
うわった　それなんのことかしら
Oh, I wonder what that's about.
決まり文句　演じきるまさに
Truly acting out the clichés.
ねだった　懐かしい思い出は
I pleaded for nostalgic memories.
絡み合って　邪魔したくなった
They intertwined and I wanted to interfere.
なんだかんだ言うが遂にだらり
Say what you will, but finally it's listless.
もう　どれもこれも嘘に見えてしまったんだ
Now everything has started to look like a lie.
どこにキミの逃げる場所が残ってる？
Where is your place to escape left?
さあ僕もあくど　キミもあくわかってんだ
Now I'm wicked, and I know you're wicked too.
One, two, one, two, three.
踊っちゃって　ナイナイ
Keep dancing, no no.
混ざっちゃった　この愛は
This love has become mixed.
針を刺して　嘘に変えよう
Let's prick it with a needle and turn it into a lie.
好きと言っちゃって　イェー
Say you like me, yeah.
詰まっちゃって　ナイナイ
Getting stuck, no no.
いつまっちゃった　この愛は
When did this love get stuck?
キミが全部　飲み干してよ
You drink it all up.
どこにいたって　イェー
No matter where you are, yeah.
もう異常だよ
It's already abnormal.
うわった　それなんのことかしら
Oh, I wonder what that's about.
しらんぷり　今日も重なるの
Feigning ignorance, it piles up again today.
汚した　誰も触れないように
I soiled it so no one could touch it.
乾くダンスだ　さぁ飲み干せ
It's a dry dance, now drink it up.
しまった　バレたのなんのことかしら
Oh no, I wonder what's been found out.
知ら切って　何度間違えば
If I feign ignorance, how many mistakes will it take?
甘かった　底なんてない沼に
It was naive, in a bottomless swamp.
溺れ切って　気づくのですか？
Will you realize after drowning completely?
誰もかれもキミのことを笑ってる
Everyone is laughing at you.
もう僕もキミが嘘に見えてしまったんだ
Now even you have started to look like a lie to me.
毒を呑むなキミのことを想ってる
Don't swallow the poison, I'm thinking of you.
さあ僕もあくど　キミもあくわかってんだ
Now I'm wicked, and I know you're wicked too.
One, two. One, two, three.
踊っちゃってライライラッ
Dance along, lie, lie, la
謝ったってもう遅い
It's too late to apologize
故意のすでに行いの共犯者さ
We're already accomplices in this deliberate act
戻れなくたっていい
It's okay if we can't turn back
染まっちゃってライライラッ
Stained in color, lie, lie, la
うだれちゃって秘め事になる
Wilting away, it becomes a secret
はじめまして罪深きよ
Nice to meet you, oh sinful one
何を言ったってイェーイ
No matter what you say, yay!
もう異常だよ
It's already abnormal
踊っちゃってライライラッ
Dance along, lie, lie, la
膨らんじゃったこの愛は
This love that has swelled up
針を刺して嘘に代えよう
Let's prick it with a needle and turn it into a lie
好きと言っちゃってイェーイ
Go ahead and say "I love you", yay!
染まっちゃってライライラッ
Stained in color, lie, lie, la
薄まっちゃったこの愛は
This love that has thinned out
君が全部飲み干してよ
You should drink it all up
どこに行っちゃったイェーイ
Where did it go? Yay!
イェーイ
Yay!
踊っちゃってライライラッ
Dance along, lie, lie, la
謝ったってもう遅い
It's too late to apologize
故意のすでに行いの共犯者さ
We're already accomplices in this deliberate act
戻れなくたっていい
It's okay if we can't turn back
染まっちゃってライライラッ
Stained in color, lie, lie, la
うだれちゃって秘め事になる
Wilting away, it becomes a secret
はじめまして罪深きよ
Nice to meet you, oh sinful one
何を言ったってイェーイ
No matter what you say, yay!
もう異常だよ
It's already abnormal
少し怖いけど
It's a little scary, but
月が綺麗だね
The moon is beautiful, isn't it?
またね
See you again
さようなら
Goodbye
トンデモワンダーズ
Shiranui Flare × Sakura Miko × Omaru Polka
Tondemo Wonders
エビバディ解体思い出に消しゴム
Everybody, dismantle! Eraser to the memories
あれ？ハイドアンドハイドアンドハイドアンドハイ
Huh? Hide and hide and hide and high
言えない！おかしな世界
I can't say it! A strange world
落とし穴にちゃんどうしよう
Fallen into a pit, oh what to do
どうしても明日も君らしくないの
No matter what, tomorrow you're still not yourself
そんな時代でいいよ 僕らまだ信じてるののの
A time like that is fine, we still believe, no, no, no
大人たちの英利のメモリー
Memories of the adults' sharp interests
悩み抱えちゃって寄り目になっちゃいそうで
Shouldering worries, I'm about to go cross-eyed
どうせ明日も全部大好きがいいじゃん
Anyway, loving everything tomorrow is fine, right?
みんなみんな笑っちゃえの音頭で
With a song to make everyone, everyone laugh
ライバル逆境モンスターだっていーじゃん
Rivals, adversity, even monsters are fine, right?
特許実家決定版を
The definitive version of the patent home
どうにもこうにも吸い込まれちゃってもいいじゃん
Even if you're sucked in one way or another, it's fine, right?
みんなみんな救っちゃわなきゃね
We have to save everyone, everyone, right?
上手く作れない笑顔だとしても
Even if it's a smile that doesn't come out right
絶対落としもしないよ
I definitely won't let it fall
わんわんでつかですエビバディショウタイム
Bow-wow, it's a mess! Everybody, showtime!
でもでもせせ永遠のモンスター
But, but, an eternal monster
わー！
Wa-!
ハイドアンドファインダーエイドじゃないならOK
If it's not a hide-and-finder aid, it's OK
まるばつ全部一斉に全中継
All circles and crosses broadcast live at once
正解も世界も大切なのメモリー
The correct answer and the world are important memories
躓く日もあるよ君をまだ否定してるのののの
There are days we stumble, but we still deny you, no, no, no
バランス前に聞いてよ待って
Listen before the balance, wait
研ぎ澄ましちゃってトンデモイーカー
Sharpened up, isn't it tondemo?
成功失敗も全部大好きでいいじゃん
Success and failure, loving them all is fine, right?
みんなみんな打ち勝つの音頭で
With a song for everyone, everyone to overcome
だってだって君ももっと笑えたじゃん
Because, because you could have laughed more
特許実況僕らは
The patent live commentary, we are
まだまだ見ない未来はこれからじゃん
The future we haven't seen yet is just beginning
みんなみんな一生仕様のポーズで
Everyone, everyone with a lifelong pose
上手く作れない笑顔だとしても
Even if it's a smile that doesn't come out right
絶対飛んで飛んで飛んでおかしな世界
Definitely fly, fly, fly into this strange world
わんわんでつかですエビバディショウタイム
Bow-wow, it's a mess! Everybody, showtime!
ツッコンデトンデドッカンデツンデモイタイ
Thrust, fly, explode, it hurts even if I'm tsundere
ツッコンデトンデドッカンデツンデモイカイ
Thrust, fly, explode, is it a tsundere medical world?
3, 2, 1, Ready Go!
3, 2, 1, わー！
3, 2, 1, Wa-!
世界買いたい終了待って待って待って
I want to buy the world, it's over, wait, wait, wait
まだまだ一生仕様のポーズで
Still, with a lifelong pose
逆1回目のそのメモリー発射
The reverse first time of that memory launch
ハッピーも失敗も消さないから
Because I won't erase the happiness or the failures
世界打ち未来超大好きでフューチャー
Striking the world, the future is super loved, future
みんなみんな笑っちゃえの世界は
A world where everyone, everyone can laugh
ライバル逆境モンスターだっていーじゃん
Rivals, adversity, even monsters are fine, right?
スーパー特許最強おかしだろ
Super patent, strongest, it's strange, right?
世界までも1回大好きで求人
Even the world once more, loved, recruiting
みんなみんな救っちゃわなきゃポーズで
With a pose to save everyone, everyone
絶対消せ消せない笑顔登場
Absolutely can't erase, a smile appears
絶対飛んで飛んでおかしな世界
Definitely fly, fly into this strange world
わんわんでつかですエビバディショウタイム
Bow-wow, it's a mess! Everybody, showtime!
Catch You Catch Me
Houshou Marine × Sakura Miko
Catch you Catch me
作詞/作曲：広瀬香美
Lyrics/Composition: Kohmi Hirose
会いたいな 会えないな
I want to see you, but I can't
切ないな この気持ち
It's so painful, this feeling
言えないの 言いたいの
I can't say it, but I want to
チャンス逃してばかり
I'm always missing my chance
だってだってだってだって
Because, because, because, because
翼広げ二人で
If the two of us spread our wings
空をマラソン 夢をユニゾンしたい
I want to marathon the sky and unison our dreams
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me 待って
Look, Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me, wait!
こっちをむいて スキだといって
Look this way and say you like me
そう Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
Yes, Nice to Meet You Good to See You, surely
私の想い あなたのハートに 飛んで飛んで飛んでいけ
May my feelings fly, fly, fly into your heart
迷わない
I won't hesitate
たまにね なくなっちゃう
Sometimes, you know, it runs out
身体のバッテリー
My body's battery
あなたの笑顔で
With your smile
いつも充電満タン パワー爆発しちゃえ
I'm always fully charged, let the power explode
お願い お願い お願い お願い
Please, please, please, please
まずはお友達から
Let's start as friends first
笑って 見つめて 楽しい毎日にしたい
Smiling, looking, I want to make every day fun
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me ゼッタイ
Look, Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me, definitely!
運命だって お似合いだって
It's fate, and we're a perfect match
そう Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
Yes, Nice to Meet You Good to See You, surely
誰にも負けない あなたに世界で 一番一番一番一番
I won't lose to anyone, you're the number one in the world to me
コイ・シ・テ・ル
I love you
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me 待って
Look, Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me, wait!
こっちをむいて スキだといって
Look this way and say you like me
そう Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
Yes, Nice to Meet You Good to See You, surely
私の想い あなたのハートに 飛んで飛んで飛んでいけ
May my feelings fly, fly, fly into your heart
迷わない
I won't hesitate
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me ゼッタイ
Look, Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me, definitely!
運命だって お似合いだって
It's fate, and we're a perfect match
そう Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
Yes, Nice to Meet You Good to See You, surely
誰にも負けない あなたに世界で 一番一番一番一番
I won't lose to anyone, you're the number one in the world to me
コイ・シ・テ・ル
I love you
約束の絆
miComet
Yakusoku no Kizuna
約束の絆
作詞：小田倉奈知 作曲：俊龍
Yakusoku no Kizuna
Lyrics: Nachi Odakura Composition: Shunryu
手のひらに掴んだ約束は
The promise I grasped in my palm
永遠に消えない宝物
Is a treasure that will never disappear
いつか見上げた空の彼方に
To the other side of the sky we once looked up at
僕らの明日へと導く
Leading us to our tomorrow
Future Star
君と共に流した涙は
The tears I shed with you
まるで夜を駆ける流星で
Are just like meteors running through the night
願い事が叶うのならば
If a wish were to come true
ひとつ大事なモノを守るよ
I'd protect one important thing
奇跡は偶然じゃない 努力の結晶で
Miracles aren't coincidences, they're the crystal of effort
どんな暗闇にも 美しい夢はあるよ
Even in any darkness, there are beautiful dreams.
もっと前へ進もう 諦めない心
Let's move forward more, with a heart that doesn't give up.
君とならば頑張れる
I can do my best if I'm with you.
無駄なことはないよ 上を向いて笑おう
Nothing is in vain, let's look up and smile.
一度きりの時間だから
Because it's a one-time thing.
忘れないよ笑顔 どんなつらい道も
I won't forget your smile, on any painful road.
いつも君がそばにいる
You're always by my side.
たどり着いた先に 何が待っていようと
No matter what awaits at the end of the journey...
明日を照らす絆は Future Star
The bond that lights up tomorrow is a Future Star.
くじけそうなひとりの夜は いつも君の笑顔を思うの
On lonely nights when I'm about to give up, I always think of your smile.
なぜか胸が熱くなるから 少し前を向いて歩けるよ
For some reason my heart gets hot, so I can walk looking a little forward.
仲間はかけがえのない 僕らの青春
Friends are irreplaceable, our youth.
二度と戻れないから 大切な歌があった
Because we can't go back, there was a precious song.
ずっと前へ進もう 光の果てまでも
Let's move forward forever, even to the end of the light.
君とならば越えられる
I can overcome it if I'm with you.
怖くなんかないよ だから強く笑おう
I'm not afraid at all, so let's smile strongly.
涙拭うおまじない
A charm to wipe away tears.
迷わないで行こう 長く険しい道も
Let's go without hesitation, on a long and steep road.
いつも君がそばにいる
You're always by my side.
どんな悲しい今日も どんな苦しい今日も
No matter how sad today is, no matter how painful today is...
明日はきっと輝く Destiny
Tomorrow will surely shine, Destiny.
もっと前へ進もう 諦めない心
Let's move forward more, with a heart that doesn't give up.
君とならば頑張れる
I can do my best if I'm with you.
無駄なことはないよ 上を向いて笑おう
Nothing is in vain, let's look up and smile.
一度きりの時間だから
Because it's a one-time thing.
忘れないよ笑顔 どんなつらい道も
I won't forget your smile, on any painful road.
いつも君がそばにいる
You're always by my side.
たどり着いた先に 何が待っていようと
No matter what awaits at the end of the journey...
明日を照らす絆は Future Star
The bond that lights up tomorrow is a Future Star.
手のひらに掴んだ約束は 永遠に消えない宝物
The promise I held in my palm is a treasure that will never disappear.
いつか見上げた空の彼方に
To the distance of the sky we once looked up at...
僕らの明日へと導く Future Star
The Future Star that leads us to our tomorrow.
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ... なんたよｗ
Yoisho, yoisho... what was that? lol
はい、ということで！はい、すいちゃんが来てくれました！
Yes, so! Yes, Suichan has come!
皆さん、こんにちは！星街すいせいです。V！
Hello everyone! I'm Hoshimachi Suisei. V!
V！イエイ！
V! Yay!
すいちゃーん！うわーー！今日も可愛いーー！今日も！可愛いーー！可愛いーー！
Suichan! Waaa! You're cute today too! Today too! Cute! Cute!
なにその間、なにその間。
What's with that pause? What's with that pause?
あ、大丈夫。大丈夫？気にしなくていい？あーー可愛いーー！
Ah, it's fine. Fine? No need to worry? Aaa, so cute!
はい、ということで、あのね、本日は何の日でしょう？はい！
Yes, so, you know, what day is it today? Yes!
え、えっと、今日何日だっけ？
Eh, let's see, what's today's date?
3月の5日。3月の5日。えー、サンゴの日。
March 5th. March 5th. Uh, Coral Day.
違う！違うな！
No! That's wrong!
え、違うの？
Eh, it's wrong?
違うのか。えー、待って、じゃあ、3と5だから...
Is it wrong? Eh, wait, then, because it's 3 and 5...
みこしの日だ！
It's Mikoshi Day!
ちげー！
No!
なんで、なんでスムーズにいかない？まだあるでしょ！あなた！
Why, why won't it go smoothly? There's more, isn't there! You!
これ、なんか、なんでお前ここに呼ばれてるんだ。なんか、あれ、なんて書いてあるの？あれ、あれ。
Wait, why was I called here? What's that, what does it say over there? That, that.
バ... バ... ボ...
Ba... Ba... Bo...
読めないの？
Can't you read it?
読めないよ、あれ。読める？あれ。
I can't read that. Can you? That.
ボスデーパーティー。
Boss Day Party.
違う、違う。バースデーパーティー。
No, no. Birthday Party.
ボッ、ツー、パーリー。
Bo- tsu- pa-ri-.
それで...
And so...
はい！
Yes!
じゃじゃーん！さくらみこの誕生日ー！
Ta-da! Sakura Miko's birthday!
うわー！すごーい！何これ、何これ、何で知らないの？！
Whoa! Awesome! What is this? What is this? Why didn't I know?!
しー、知らなかった？あれ、だってなんか、あの依頼書に書いてなかったけど。
Shh, you didn't know? Well, because, like, it wasn't written in the request form.
おい！依頼書とか言うな、依頼書とか！
Hey! Don't say "request form"! Or "request form"!
あれあれ、そうなんだ。おめでとう、おめでとう！
Oh, is that so? Congratulations, congratulations!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
なんかそういえば渡せって言われてたもんがあったような...
Come to think of it, I think there was something I was told to give you...
え、何？
Eh, what?
用意してきてくれたの？さすがすいちゃんなんだが。
You prepared something for me? As expected of Sui-chan.
大丈夫それ？大丈夫それ？
Is that okay? Is that okay?
お、すごい。大丈夫それ？
Oh, wow. Is that okay?
あー、落ちる、落ちる！ほらほら、するな、するな！
Ah, it's falling, it's falling! Hey, don't do that, don't do that!
はいみこち、これ、みこちへのケーキ。おい！
Here Mikochi, this is the cake for Mikochi. Hey!
おい！どうしたの？！
Hey! What's wrong?!
おかしいだろ！
This is wrong!
いや、そりゃ誕生日と言えば、ケーキ投げでしょ。
Well, for a birthday, it's gotta be a cake fight.
ケーキ投げすんじゃないよ、お前、陽キャかよ！
Don't throw cakes! Are you some kind of extrovert?!
え、嘘、嘘、嘘。今のは張りぼてで、もう一個ちゃんとね、あるんだって。
Eh, just kidding, just kidding. That was a prop, and there's another proper one.
ほら、ほら、これは本物だよ。
Look, look, this is the real deal.
本当かな？
Is it real?
本当だよ。
It is.
はい、食べて、食べて。
Here, eat it, eat it.
食べ切りましたー。
I finished it all!
めっちゃ食った。
I ate so much.
はい、皿投げるよ。
Okay, I'm throwing the plate.
はい、さよなら。
Here, bye.
一気に食うと、気持ち悪くなっちまう。
Eating it all at once makes me feel sick.
そうだろうね。
I bet.
でもありがとうございました。美味しかったね。
But thank you. It was delicious.
美味しかった。
It was delicious.
よかった、よかった。スタッフが作りました。
Good, good. The staff made it.
ありがとうスタッフ！ありがとうスタッフ！
Thanks, staff! Thanks, staff!
すいちゃんはね、渡せって言われただけです。
Sui-chan was just told to deliver it.
あ！言うんじゃないよ、ビジネスでしょ、ビジネス！
Ah! Don't say that! It's business, business!
ビジネス、あ、なんかそういえば。
Business. Oh, come to think of it.
YouTube Liveでは、みこめっと揃うの、初めてらしいですね。
It seems this is the first time MiComet has appeared together on YouTube Live.
あ、じゃなんか、この面子そんなに珍しいもんではないけど。
Oh? Well, this combination isn't that rare though.
そうなんですよ。ちょっとね、お仕事とか、お仕事とか、お仕事で。いつもありがとうございます。
That's right. Just, like, for work, and work, and work. Thanks as always.
あ、どうも。
Oh, you're welcome.
よくね、ライブさせてもらってます、二人で。
We often do lives together, the two of us.
また誘ってください。
Please invite me again.
ぜひ！
Definitely!
こうやって、普通にコラボしたりするのは...
So, collaborating normally like this is...
お初？
The first time?
お初ですね！イェーイ！
The first time! Yay!
嬉しいか？嬉しい、みんな？イェーイ！
Are you happy? Is everyone happy? Yay!
なんか最近、需要が高まってきたらしいよ。
I heard the demand has been increasing lately.
何が？
For what?
みこめっと。
MiComet.
そっか。なんかね、ファンアートとかね、増えてきて。
I see. Like, fan art and stuff has been increasing.
おー。すごいらしいよ。嬉しいか。
Oh. Apparently so. Are you happy?
あ、媚びとこ、媚びとこ。
Oh, let's play it up, play it up.
はい、みこめっと。
Yes, MiComet.
はい、みこめっとね。
やっぱ客と一緒に撮ったりもする？
Should we take a picture with the audience too?
あ、いいよ。
Ah, sure.
そそそ。じゃあこっち向いてもらって。
Yeah. Then turn this way.
はい、カメラさん。
Okay, Mr. Camera.
可愛いー、みこめっと。
So cute, MiComet.
みこめっと。可愛い。
MiComet. So cute.
可愛いね。あ、喜んでる、ほら。
So cute. Oh, they're happy, look.
やっぱ嬉しいんだ、みんなね、みこめっと。
Everyone's really happy after all, for MiComet.
嬉しい、みんな。
Everyone's happy.
キャピ、キャピ。なんかポーズ取ろう。
Kyapi, kyapi. Let's do a pose.
いいよ。あ、媚びろよ、すいちゃんの。
Sure. Oh, play it up, Sui-chan.
え、え、ああ。
Eh, eh, ah.
いいじゃん、はい、チーズ！
Nice, okay, cheese!
お仕事なら、お仕事なら。
If it's for work, if it's for work.
あ、可愛い！いいじゃないですか。
Oh, cute! Isn't that great?
これは沸きましたね。はい、これは沸きましたね、皆さん。
This definitely hyped everyone up. Yes, everyone's hyped.
じゃあ、あのさ、ケーキ。
Now, well, the cake.
ケーキと一緒に撮りたい。
I want to take a picture with the cake.
ケーキはもうあんたが食べてしもたって。え、予備があるんですか？
You already ate the cake. Eh, is there a spare?
よかった、よかった。はい、予備、予備。
Good, good. Yes, the spare, the spare.
イェーイ！はい、予備のケーキ。じゃあ、このステージ見せながら、こうやって撮りたい。
Yay! Okay, the spare cake. Then, I want to take a picture while showing this stage.
なるほど。
I see.
はい、じゃあカメラさん。ケーキがこんな感じ。
Okay, Mr. Camera. The cake is like this.
よし。はい、可愛く、可愛いポーズ。
Okay. Yes, cute, a cute pose.
可愛いポーズ。
A cute pose.
えー、すごーい！可愛いかも！
Oh, awesome! It might be cute!
あ、いい、いいアングル！いいアングル！
Oh, good, a good angle! A good angle!
ありがとう、すいちゃん。
Thank you, Sui-chan.
いいとこだよ。プルプルしてる。いいとこだよ。あ、落ちたー！
It's at a good point. It's shaking. It's at a good point. Oh, it fell!
落とすんじゃないよ、食べ物を！
Don't drop the food!
食べ物じゃない、あれ、張りぼてだから。
It's not food, that was a prop.
あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, I see.
はい、ということでね。はい、すいちゃんに来てもらいましたと。
So, there we go. Yes, we had Sui-chan join us.
本当にどうもありがとうございました。
Thank you very much indeed.
いえいえ、では定時なので、帰らせていただきます。ありがとうございました。
No problem, but my time is up, so I'll be heading back. Thank you.
定時かよ！バイバーイ！またねー！
Time's up?! Bye-bye! See ya!
ということで、定時で帰ってしまったということで。
So, she went home because her shift ended.
じゃあ、みこちゃんもね、お着替えしてこようと思います。
Well, I'm going to go change my outfit too.
みんな待っててー。すいちゃーん、待ってー！
Everyone, please wait! Sui-chan, wait for me!
逃げてちゃダメ
Don't run away
避けてちゃダメ
Don't avoid it
後悔なんてしたくない
I don't want to have any regrets
LET'S GO!
らしく進もう
Let's move forward as we are
みんなー！
Everyone!
見て！新しい髪型だよ！
Look! It's a new hairstyle!
後半も
The second half...
盛り上がっていくぞー！
...is gonna be a blast!
GOOD DAY 目覚ましより
GOOD DAY, even before the alarm
早起きの SUNNY DAY
an early-riser SUNNY DAY
今日は いつもよりも
Today, more than usual
ちょっとおしゃれ頑張った
I tried a bit harder to look cute
なのに全然 君は全然
But not at all, you not at all
気づかないで よそ見してるんだ
Notice me, you're looking elsewhere
知らない 乙女心
A maiden's heart you don't know
教えてあげる
I'll teach it to you
君が好き！素直になって
I like you! Being honest
言えたらどんなに SO HAPPY
If I could say it, I'd be SO HAPPY
溢れ出す この愛は
This love that's overflowing
甘いだけではありません！
Is not just sweet!
明日が今日より輝いて
May tomorrow shine brighter than today
幸せになれますように
And may we be happy
ちょっとくらい つよがりな
Even if I'm a little bit...
ところも許してください
...stubborn, please forgive me
逃げてちゃダメ
Don't run away
避けてちゃダメ
Don't avoid it
後悔なんてしたくない
I don't want to have any regrets
LET'S GO HAPPY
らしく進もう
Let's move forward as we are
なんで！？ついてなくて
Why!? My luck is down
へんてこ RAINY DAY
on this weird RAINY DAY
お気に入りの靴
In my favorite shoes
水たまり ガッカリ
Stepping in a puddle, what a bummer
なのに突然 君が突然
But suddenly, you suddenly
振り返った その笑顔で
Turned around with that smile
熱くなっていく 頬に
As my cheeks start to flush
気づかないでね
Please don't notice
君の手と手が 触れ合って
When our hands touch
伝わってるよ もう MY SWEET
I can feel it already, MY SWEET
溢れ出す この愛を
This love that's overflowing
甘い果実に育てたい！
I want to grow it into sweet fruit!
今日うまく いかなくたって
Even if things don't go well today
明日から変われるように
So that things can change tomorrow
ちょっとだけ 弱気でも
Even if I'm a little timid
私を照らしてください
Please shine your light on me
涙ふいて
Wiping my tears
上を向いて
Looking up
止まってなんていられない
I can't just stay still
LET'S GO HAPPY
らしく進もう
Let's move forward as we are
昨日までの 自分にさよなら
Goodbye to the me of yesterday
明日は
Tomorrow...
きっと
...surely...
明日の
...tomorrow's...
太陽が照らすよ
...sun will shine down
君が好き！素直になって
I like you! Being honest
言えたらどんなに SO HAPPY
If I could say it, I'd be SO HAPPY
溢れ出す この愛は
This love that's overflowing
甘いだけではありません！
Is not just sweet!
明日が今日より輝いて
May tomorrow shine brighter than today
幸せになれますように
And may we be happy
ちょっとくらい つよがりな
Even if I'm a little bit...
ところも許してください
...stubborn, please forgive me
逃げてちゃダメ
Don't run away
避けてちゃダメ
Don't avoid it
後悔なんてしたくない
I don't want to have any regrets
LET'S GO HAPPY
らしく進もう
Let's move forward as we are
銀河の隅で 惑星は
In a corner of the galaxy, the planets...
ぐるぐる回る
...go 'round and 'round
電波の記録 エコーが
A record of radio waves, an echo...
返ってきた これで何回だ
...came back, how many times has it been?
遠くの宇宙で あなたに
In a distant space...
恋をしたんだ
...I fell in love with you
届かないこと
That I won't reach you...
理解しているのに
...is something I understand, yet...
あーあなたに会いたいな って
Ah, "I want to see you," that...
気持ちがループループする
...feeling loops and loops
あたまが どうにかなりそうだ
I feel like I'm going crazy
それ以外 交わせない
I can't exchange anything else
あー今すぐ 会いたいな って
Ah, "I want to see you right now," that...
来る日もループループする
...day after day, loops and loops
この周回軌道上に
On this orbit...
あなたがいなくても
...even if you aren't here
そこに大体愛があるだけ
There's mostly just love there
声を辿って何光年だ
How many light-years has it been, following your voice?
延長線に消えてゆく
Fading into the line of extension.
このままパッと忘れられたら
If I could just forget everything in an instant...
楽だろうな
...it would be so easy.
触れられないのに見えてしまって
Even though I can't touch you, I can see you,
どうしようもないや
and there's nothing I can do about it.
近くて遠いあなただ
You're so close, yet so far.
分かってるよ
I know.
あぁ それでも会いたいな
Ah, even so, I want to see you,
って 何度もループする
those thoughts loop over and over.
心があなたで鳴っている
My heart is ringing with thoughts of you.
それだけが確かだ
That's the only thing that's certain.
それだけでいいよ
That's all that matters.
あぁ 星が回るように
Ah, just like the stars rotating,
僕らはループする
we continue to loop.
想いが軌道を描いている
My feelings are tracing an orbit,
あなただけを追うよ
chasing only after you.
あぁ 今すぐ会いたいな
Ah, I want to see you right now,
って 命がループする
and so my life loops.
この周回軌道上に
On this circular orbit,
あなたがいなくても
even if you aren't there,
それ以外思えない
I can't think of anything else.
そこに大体、愛が在るだけ
There's mostly just love there.
みこぴ～ いつも支えてくれてありがとう!! だいすきだよ☆
Mikopi~ Thank you for always supporting me!! I love you so much☆
そこに大体 愛が在るだけ
There's mostly just love there.
あはー！
Aha!
はい、ということで、みんな！どうですか？
All right, so, everyone! How is it?
この髪型、可愛いでしょう？
This hairstyle is cute, isn't it?
イェーイ！
Yay!
みんなありがとう、ありがとう。
Thank you everyone, thank you.
ということで、皆さんここまでやってきましたけど、もう後半戦に突入しております。
So, we've come this far, but we're already entering the second half.
皆さんどうですか？楽しんでる？
How is everyone doing? Are you having fun?
あ！みんななんか語彙力がなくなってるよ。
Ah! It looks like everyone's lost their vocabulary.
可愛いですしか言ってないよ。
You're only saying "You're cute."
まあ可愛いからね、みこは。
Well, Miko is cute, after all.
はい、ということで、
All right, and so,
えーこのパートはね、もうちょっと、ちょっと短いんで、急ぎ足で皆さんに、
this part is a bit short, so I'll go through this quickly.
えーこの後2曲ぐらいね、すごいね、あの、みこがみんながあの、歌ってくれたり、まダンスしたら嬉しいだろうなっていう、ま曲があるんですけど、
After this, there are about two songs that Miko thinks everyone would be happy to see me sing and dance to,
その前に、みこは今、まちょっと急ぎ、急ぎ足、急ぎ足で、告知をしたいと思います！
but before that, I'd like to make an announcement in a bit of a hurry!
それでは、告知、どうぞ！
So, here's the announcement!
あ、どうぞ！
Here it is!
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
はい、えーさくらみこ誕生日記念2022、誕生日記念、えーフルセットが発売します！やったー！
Yes! Sakura Miko Birthday Celebration 2022. The Birthday Celebration Full Set is going on sale! Yay!
はい、ということで、じゃあ紹介していきますね。うし！
All right, then, I'll introduce them. Okay!
はい、こちらドドーン！
Yes, here they are, boom!
えーまずですね、ラバーマット。そして、あのビッグシルエットTシャツ。
First, there's a rubber mat. And that big-silhouette T-shirt.
キーホルダー、みこぴのぬいぐるみ！やったー！
A key holder, and a Mikopi plushie! Yay!
そして、ポストカード。はい、という感じのフルセットになっております。
And a postcard. Yes, those make up the full set.
続いて、はい。
Next, yes.
こちらは、おるだん先生が描いてくれました。
This one was drawn by Orudan-sensei.
このね、あの誕生日パーティーの後みたいなみこのラバーマットです。やったー！
It's a rubber mat of Miko after the birthday party. Yay!
可愛い！絶対買う！
It's so cute! I'm definitely buying it!
では続いてドン！
Now, next, boom!
そして、みんな見て！Tシャツだよ。
And look, everyone! It's a T-shirt.
はい、こちらはですね、大川ぶくぶ先生に描いていただいたよ！
Yes, this one was drawn by Okawa Bukubu-sensei!
わー、これはもう普段使いができるな。
Wow, this is something you can use every day.
ここで、あの「にゃっはろー」って言います。
It says "Nyahallo" here.
めっちゃ可愛いよね！これめっちゃ可愛いよね！
It's so cute! This is so cute!
これみんな買ってね、普段使いしてね。ぜひ普段使いできるよね。
Everyone, please buy this and use it every day. You can definitely use it for everyday wear.
ここに後ろにはね、みこが赤ちゃんになってます。
On the back here, Miko is a baby.
はい、続いてこちら。
All right, next is this.
これは、えーみこぴ、そして金時、そして味ぽんずとね、みこが描きました。
This one features Mikopi, Kintoki, and Ajipon-zu, drawn by Miko.
こちらキーホルダーになってます。みんな買ってね！
This is a key holder. Please buy one, everyone!
3連結キーホルダー
3-Piece Keychain Set
手描き。そして、こちら！
Hand-drawn. And this!
35Pぬいぐるみ
35P Plushie
ドン！ついに、みこぴーのぬいぐるみが、出たよー！
Ta-da! Finally, the Mikopi plushie is here!
めっちゃ嬉しい！めっちゃ可愛いよね！
I'm so happy! It's so cute, right?
可愛い。これ可愛いな。みんな嬉しいな。
Cute. This is cute. Everyone's happy.
はい、ということでね。このもっちりとした、あのみこぴーのぬいぐるみなので、みんな買ってください。
Yes, so, since it's this squishy Mikopi plushie, everyone please buy it.
はい。みこが一番嬉しい。
Yes. Miko is the happiest.
はい、そして... なんと！なんと、なんと、なんと！ドドン！
Yes, and... what's more! What's more, what's more, what's more! Da-da-da-dun!
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
なんと、フルセット購入特典では...
Surprisingly, for the full set purchase bonus...
このポストカードに... え、じ... 直筆サイン入りポストカード？
On this postcard... eh, hand-signed postcard?
え、みんなに？みんなに？みんなに？届くって、マジ？うわー！
Eh, to everyone? Everyone? Everyone? It'll reach everyone? Seriously? Whoa!
はい、ということでね。まあ今回は争いが起きません。
Yes, so. Well, this time there will be no fighting.
とても平和な、直筆サイン。
Very peaceful, hand-signed.
ということで、みこはまた監禁されますけど、みんなにね...
So, Miko will be confined again, but to everyone...
感謝の気持ちを込めて、書きたいと思いますので、みんな買ってね！
I want to write with feelings of gratitude, so everyone buy it!
買ってね！直筆欲しいか？欲しいよな！
Buy it! Do you want a hand-signed one? You do, right!
はい、ということで。それでは、最後の曲。
Yes, so. Now, the final song.
気持ちを込めて歌って踊るので、みんな見ててね！
I'll sing and dance with all my heart, so everyone watch!
好きになって、もっと！
Fall in love with me more!
私を見て、もっと！
Look at me more!
恩返しは、愛のこもった投げキッスで！
My return for your kindness is a love-filled blown kiss!
気のせいじゃない、目は合ってるよ。
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting.
ハート作って、返しちゃってください。
Make a heart and send it back to me, please.
やれること、なんでもします。
I'll do anything I can.
NGなしで、体当たり挑戦！
No NGs, a full-body challenge!
エゴサで見つけた、アンチのコメ。
Anti comments I found while searching for myself.
ふざけんじゃねえよ、分かってるし。
Don't mess with me, I know already.
でも大丈夫、ここに立てばみんながいる。
But it's okay, when I stand here, everyone is here.
行くよ！
Here we go!
好きになって、もっと！
Fall in love with me more!
私を見て、もっと！
Look at me more!
恩返しは、愛のこもった投げキッスで！
My return for your kindness is a love-filled blown kiss!
虜にする！もっと！
I'll captivate you! More!
夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll show you a dream! More!
楽しんでって、愛のこもったスペシャルナイト！
Enjoy yourself, a love-filled special night!
ファンサしちゃうぞ！
I'm going to give you some fanservice!
お手紙も、書いてください。
Please write me letters too.
何度も読んで、心にしまします。
I'll read them many times and keep them in my heart.
スキャンダル、まだ早いけど。
Scandals, it's still too early but...
裏切りません、宣言しときます。
I won't betray you, I'll declare it now.
嫉妬嫌がらせには負けない。
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment.
ふざけんじゃねえ、実力で勝ってやる。
Don't mess with me, I'll win with my own strength.
だからやめない、負けず嫌い、私はいる。
So I won't stop, I'm a sore loser, I'm here.
行くよ！
Here we go!
拳上げて、もっと！
Raise your fists more!
汗をかいて、もっと！
Sweat more!
恩返しは、愛のこもったみこビームで！
My return for your kindness is a love-filled Miko Beam!
大歓声、もっと！
Great cheers, more!
まだまだだね、もっと！
Not there yet, more!
受け止めてね、愛のこもったわがままソング！
Accept it, please, a love-filled selfish song!
ファンサしちゃうぞ！
I'm going to give you some fanservice!
はぁ... 終わりが近づく、寂しいね。
Haa... the end is near, it's lonely, isn't it.
楽しいのに、泣きそうだよ。
Even though it's fun, I feel like crying.
次も、次も、また会えるよね？
Next time, and the time after, we can meet again, right?
約束！
Promise!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
優しさに触れているからこそ。
It's precisely because I'm touched by kindness.
心ない誰かの言葉さえも。
Even the heartless words of someone.
必要なんだ、必要なんだ、強くなろう。
Are necessary, are necessary, let's become stronger.
好きになって、もっと！
Fall in love with me more!
楽しんじゃえ、もっと！
Let's enjoy ourselves more!
忘れないで、特別な日になりますように。
Don't forget, I hope it becomes a special day.
共に歌おう ずっと
Let's sing together forever
共に歩もう ずっと
Let's walk together forever
合言葉は
The password is
とびっきりの L・O・V・E
A very special L-O-V-E
好きになって！もっと
Fall in love with me! More!
私を見て！もっと
Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもった投げキッス”で
My way of giving back is with an "affectionate blown kiss"
虜にする！もっと
I'll captivate you! More!
夢を見せる！もっと
I'll show you more dreams! More!
楽しんでって 愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Please enjoy this special night filled with love
ファンサしちゃうぞ(っ・ω・)っ
I'm going to give you some fan service!
サクラカゼ
Sakura Kaze (Cherry Blossom Breeze)
箱にあたる陽を 横目で眺めて
Gazing sideways at the sun hitting the box
そっと陰る木の根に 一人で比べてた
Comparing myself alone to the softly shading tree roots
積もる溜息を 吹き払うように
As if to blow away the accumulating sighs
そんな私を君が 見つけてくれたんだ
That's when you found me
そう それは恋のような ぬくもりを全部
Yes, it's like all the warmth of love
君に笑顔咲かせたら
If I can make you smile
桜風に踊る空 君と出会ったこの場所で
In the sky dancing with the cherry blossom breeze, in this place where I met you
どれくらいの思い出ぎゅっと 溢れそうになるかな
How many memories will overflow as I hold them tight?
君と流した涙は 明日の笑顔の糧にしよう
Let's turn the tears shed with you into food for tomorrow's smiles
膝をついてたって ほら 何度だっていいよ
Even if I'm on my knees, see, it's okay, however many times
意地を張って 恥をかいて いじけたって それでも
Being stubborn, being embarrassed, even sulking, still
君がそばで見守ってくれたこと
That you were there by my side watching over me
わかってるから
I know that
追い風を受けて とまらない日々も
Taking the tailwind, through the unstoppable days
そっと挫けそうになって 心が渦巻いた
My heart swirled as I felt like I was softly breaking
積もる溜息でまた 泣きかけても
Even if I'm about to cry again from the accumulating sighs
あたたかな手でずっと 支えてくれたんだ
You've always supported me with your warm hands
ほら
See
耳をすませば 一人じゃないから
If you listen closely, you're not alone
諦めかけて 心が閉じても
Even if I'm about to give up and my heart closes
君が背中を押してくれたよね
You gave me a push on the back, didn't you?
春のつぼみが花開く頃
When the spring buds bloom
隣で笑い合おうね
Let's laugh together side by side
桜風に踊る空 君と出会ったこの場所で
In the sky dancing with the cherry blossom breeze, in this place where I met you
どれくらいの思い出ぎゅっと 溢れそうになるかな
How many memories will overflow as I hold them tight?
君と描くこの花は 未来もきっと残るから
This flower I draw with you will surely remain in the future
汗をかいた分は そうさ 強くなれるんだ
The more I sweat, the stronger I'll become
意地を張って 恥をかいて いじけたって それでも
Being stubborn, being embarrassed, even sulking, still
君がそばで見守ってくれたから
Because you were there by my side watching over me
ありがとうだよ
Thank you
みんな！誕生日祝ってくれて本当にありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you so much for celebrating my birthday!
これからも頑張るぞ！
I'll keep doing my best!
君と出会えたこの空 これからももっと咲かせるよ
This sky where I met you, I'll make it bloom even more from now on
この後すぐ
Coming up soon
メンバー限定
Members only